[{"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/1.sparql", "number": 1, "question": "How many hospitals are there in Oxford?", "answer": "   select (count(DISTINCT ?x ) as ?total) where {           ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_hospital_103540595>.           ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Oxford>. } \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/2.sparql", "number": 2, "question": "How many underground lines does London have?", "answer": "select distinct (count(distinct ?x)as ?total)\nwhere {\n          ?x a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wikicat_London_Underground_lines>.\n          \n}"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/3.sparql", "number": 3, "question": "How many counties does England have?", "answer": "   select (count(distinct ?x) as ?totalCounty) where {               ?x  ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_county_108546183>.              ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/4.sparql", "number": 4, "question": "Which restaurants are close to London Bridge?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?poi WHERE   {  ?city geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom;                    osm:has_name \"London Bridge\"^^xsd:string;                    a osm:Attraction.         ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT        ?instanceWKT.         ?poi rdf:type osm:Restaurant ;              geo:hasGeometry ?poiGeom .         ?poiGeom  geo:asWKT        ?poiWKT .              FILTER(geof:distance(?poiWKT, ?instanceWKT, uom:metre) < 1000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/5.sparql", "number": 5, "question": "Is there any hospital in a range of 1 km from Jubilee Gardens in London?", "answer": "   ASK{  ?city geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom;                    osm:has_name \"Jubilee Gardens\"^^xsd:string;                   a osm:Park.        ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT        ?instanceWKT.        ?poi rdf:type osm:Hospital ;             geo:hasGeometry ?poiGeom .        ?poiGeom  geo:asWKT        ?poiWKT .             FILTER(geof:distance(?poiWKT, ?instanceWKT, uom:metre) < 1000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/6.sparql", "number": 6, "question": "Which counties border county Lincolnshire?", "answer": "   select ?county where {  ?lincolnshire  rdf:type  <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>;   <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/hasOS_Name> \"Lincolnshire County\";    <http://www.opengis.net/ont/geosparql#hasGeometry> ?geomLC.   ?geomLC geo:asWKT ?lcWKT.   ?county  rdf:type  <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>;     <http://www.opengis.net/ont/geosparql#hasGeometry> ?geomC.      ?geomC geo:asWKT ?cWKT.    FILTER(geof:sfTouches(?lcWKT, ?cWKT)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/7.sparql", "number": 7, "question": "Where is Loch Goil located?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1WKT WHERE {     <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Loch_Goil> geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.     ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/8.sparql", "number": 8, "question": "Which bridges cross river Thames?", "answer": "   select distinct ?bridges where {  ?bridges a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_bridge_102898711>.  ?bridges <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/crosses> ?o.     FILTER CONTAINS(str(?o),\"Thames\"). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/9.sparql", "number": 9, "question": "What is the number of universities in London?", "answer": "   select (count(distinct ?x)as ?total) where { ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_university_108286569>. ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>.} \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/10.sparql", "number": 10, "question": "Which rivers are in Wales?", "answer": "   select distinct ?river where {        ?river rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.         ?river <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wales> . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/11.sparql", "number": 11, "question": "Which counties of Scotland border England?", "answer": "   select distinct ?county  where {                                         ?county rdf:type <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>;                                                 geo:hasGeometry ?cGeom.                                         ?cGeom geo:asWKT ?cWKT.                                         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>         geo:hasGeometry ?geom.                                         ?geom geo:asWKT ?iWKT.                                         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>                geo:hasGeometry ?geom1.                                          ?geom1 geo:asWKT ?iWKT1.                                         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?cWKT,?iWKT) && geof:sfTouches(?cWKT,?iWKT1) )  }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/12.sparql", "number": 12, "question": "Where is Nelson's Column located?", "answer": "   SELECT ?geomWKT WHERE {     ?entity osm:has_name \"Nelson's Column\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>;             <http://www.opengis.net/ont/geosparql#hasGeometry> ?geom.     ?geom  geo:asWKT ?geomWKT. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/13.sparql", "number": 13, "question": "Does the county of Durham border Essex?", "answer": "   ASK {            <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Essex> <http://www.opengis.net/ont/geosparql#sfTouches> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/County_Durham>. } \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/14.sparql", "number": 14, "question": "Which restaurants are at most 1km away from Big Ben?", "answer": "   SELECT ?restaurant WHERE {        ?bigBen osm:has_name \"Big Ben\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>;          geo:hasGeometry ?bigBenGeom.  ?bigBenGeom  geo:asWKT ?bigBenGeomWKT. ?restaurant rdf:type osm:Restaurant;      osm:has_name ?restaurantName;        geo:hasGeometry ?restaurantGeom.  ?restaurantGeom geo:asWKT ?restaurantGeomWKT.  FILTER (geof:distance(?restaurantGeomWKT, ?bigBenGeomWKT, uom:metre) < 1000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/15.sparql", "number": 15, "question": "Is county Oxfordshire east of the county Essex?", "answer": "   ASK { ?oxfordshire <http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label> ?l ;         geo:hasGeometry ?geo1 .         filter(str(?l)=\"Oxfordshire\").  ?geo1 geo:asWKT ?wkt1 .         ?essex <http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label> ?l2 ;         geo:hasGeometry ?geo2 .         ?geo2 geo:asWKT ?wkt2 .         filter(str(?l2)=\"Essex\").         FILTER(strdf:left(?wkt1,?wkt2)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/16.sparql", "number": 16, "question": "Which pubs in Dublin are near Guinness Brewery?", "answer": "   Select distinct ?pub WHERE {  ?pub a osm:Pub ; geo:hasGeometry ?pubGeo . ?pubGeo geo:asWKT ?pubWKT . ?dublin osm:has_name ?l2 ; geo:hasGeometry ?dublinGeo . ?dublinGeo geo:asWKT ?dublinWKT . ?guiness osm:has_name ?l; geo:hasGeometry ?guinessGeo . ?guinessGeo geo:asWKT ?guinessWKT . filter( str(?l2)=\"Dublin\"). filter( str(?l)=\"Guinness Brewery\"). filter(geof:distance(?guinessWKT, ?pubWKT, uom:metre)<1000). filter(geof:sfContains(?dublinWKT, ?pubWKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/17.sparql", "number": 17, "question": "Which hospitals in Liverpool are near Abercromby Square?", "answer": "   Select distinct ?hospital WHERE { ?hospital a osm:Hospital ; geo:hasGeometry ?hospitalGeo .  ?hospitalGeo geo:asWKT ?hospitalWKT . ?Liverpool <http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label>  ?l2 ; geo:hasGeometry ?LiverpoolGeo . ?LiverpoolGeo geo:asWKT ?LiverpoolWKT . ?Abercromby osm:has_name ?l; geo:hasGeometry ?AbercrombyGeo . ?AbercrombyGeo geo:asWKT ?AbercrombyWKT . filter( str(?l2)=\"Liverpool\"). filter( str(?l)=\"Abercromby Square\"). filter(geof:sfContains(?LiverpoolWKT, ?hospitalWKT)). filter (geof:distance(?hospitalWKT, ?AbercrombyWKT, uom:metre) < 1000). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/18.sparql", "number": 18, "question": "Which cafes in London are at most 3 km from St. Anthony the Great and St. John the Baptist church?", "answer": "   Select distinct ?cafe WHERE { ?cafe a osm:Cafe ; geo:hasGeometry ?cafeGeo . ?cafeGeo geo:asWKT ?cafeWKT . ?London <http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#label>  ?l2 ; geo:hasGeometry ?LondonGeo . ?LondonGeo geo:asWKT ?LondonWKT . ?church osm:has_name ?l; geo:hasGeometry ?churchGeo . ?churchGeo geo:asWKT ?churchWKT . filter( str(?l2)=\"London\"). filter( str(?l)=\"St. Anthony the Great & St. John the Baptist\"). filter(geof:sfContains(?LondonWKT, ?cafeWKT)). filter (geof:distance(?cafeWKT, ?churchWKT, uom:metre) < 3000). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/19.sparql", "number": 19, "question": "Which department stores are at most 2km from Central Park hotel in London?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?city WHERE{      ?city geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom;                   osm:has_name \"London\"^^xsd:string;                   rdf:type osm:City.     ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT ?cWKT.      ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?poiGeom;                   osm:has_name \"Central Park Hotel\"^^xsd:string;                   a osm:Hotel.        ?poiGeom geo:asWKT        ?poiWKT.    ?dept a osm:Department_Store;           geo:hasGeometry ?dGeom.      ?dGeom geo:asWKT ?dWKT.    FILTER(geof:sfContains(?cWKT, ?poiWKT) && geof:distance(?dWKT,?cWKT,uom:metre) <= 2000 ) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/20.sparql", "number": 20, "question": "Which universities are in county Essex?", "answer": "   select distinct ?university  where {             ?university rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_university_108286569>.             ?university <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Essex>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/21.sparql", "number": 21, "question": "Is there a church at most 2km from the University of Westminster?", "answer": "   ASK { ?s2 <http://data.linkedeodata.eu/ontology#has_name> \"University of Westminster\"^^xsd:string. ?s2 rdf:type osm:University .  ?s2 geo:hasGeometry ?geo2 . ?geo2 geo:asWKT ?w2 . ?s3 geo:hasGeometry ?geo3 . ?s3 <http://data.linkedeodata.eu/ontology#has_name> ?name . ?geo3 geo:asWKT ?w3 . ?s3 rdf:type osm:Church.  filter(geof:distance(?w3,?w2, uom:metre) < 2000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/22.sparql", "number": 22, "question": "Is there a mountain in the county of Greater Manchester taller than 1300 meters above sea level?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x  where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_mountain_109359803>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Greater_Manchester>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/elevationm>  ?property.                                 FILTER(xsd:integer(str(?property)) > 1300) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/23.sparql", "number": 23, "question": "Which mountains in Scotland have height more than 1000 meters?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_mountain_109359803>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/elevationm>  ?property.                                 FILTER(xsd:integer(str(?property)) > 1000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/24.sparql", "number": 24, "question": "What's the name of the river that runs through London?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?name WHERE {         ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.         ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>.         ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/name> ?name. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/25.sparql", "number": 25, "question": "How many cities does Thames river crosses?", "answer": "   SELECT (count(distinct ?x) as ?total) WHERE {         ?city rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/River_Thames> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?city. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/26.sparql", "number": 26, "question": "Which districts border London?", "answer": "   select distinct ?district  where {                                          ?district rdf:type <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_District>;                                                  geo:hasGeometry ?cGeom.                                          ?cGeom geo:asWKT ?cWKT.                                          ?lon owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>;         geo:hasGeometry ?geom.                                          ?geom geo:asWKT ?iWKT.                                         FILTER( geof:sfTouches(?cWKT,?iWKT1) ) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/27.sparql", "number": 27, "question": "Which are the metropolitan counties of England?", "answer": "   not available\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/28.sparql", "number": 28, "question": "What is the name of the river that flows under the Queensway Bridge in Liverpool?", "answer": "   Not enough information available \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/29.sparql", "number": 29, "question": "Is Hampshire north of Berkshire?", "answer": "   ASK { <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Hampshire> geo:hasGeometry ?iGeometry1. ?iGeometry1 geo:asWKT ?iWKT1. ?y owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Berkshire>; geo:hasGeometry ?iGeometry2. ?iGeometry2 geo:asWKT ?iWKT2. FILTER(strdf:above(?iWKT1, ?iWKT2)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/30.sparql", "number": 30, "question": "Is there any stadium in Cardiff?", "answer": "   select distinct ?st where {         ?st rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_stadium_104295881> .         ?st <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Cardiff> . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/31.sparql", "number": 31, "question": "Which aerodromes are at most 50km from London?", "answer": "   SELECT ?airport WHERE {  ?airport rdf:type osm:Airport .  ?airport osm:has_name ?name .  ?airport geo:hasGeometry  ?poiGeom .  ?poiGeom  geo:asWKT ?poiWKT .  ?instance <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago-extension/ontology/hasGADM_Name> \"London\"@en.  ?instance geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom .  ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT ?instanceWKT .   FILTER( geof:distance(?poiWKT, ?instanceWKT, uom:metre) < 50000 ) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/32.sparql", "number": 32, "question": "How many rivers cross the county West Yorkshire?", "answer": "   SELECT (count(distinct ?x)as ?total) WHERE {          ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.          ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/West_Yorkshire>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/33.sparql", "number": 33, "question": "Which are the counties of Northern Ireland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?counties where {         ?counties rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_county_108546183>.         ?counties <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Northern_Ireland>.                       }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/34.sparql", "number": 34, "question": "Is there a National Park in England?", "answer": "   select distinct ?np where {         ?np rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_park_108615149>.         ?np <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/type> ?o.         ?np <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn>+ ?o1.         FILTER (CONTAINS(str(?o),\"National park\") OR CONTAINS(str(?o),\"nationalpark\") OR CONTAINS(str(?o),\"national park\") and CONTAINS(str(?o1),\"England\") ) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/35.sparql", "number": 35, "question": "Is Cavan a county of Ireland?", "answer": "   ASK {          <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/County_Cavan> ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wikicat_Counties_of_Ireland>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/36.sparql", "number": 36, "question": "Which lakes are in Ireland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?lakes where {        ?lakes rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_lake_109328904>.        ?lakes <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/37.sparql", "number": 37, "question": "Are there cities that are at most 2km away from St. David's in Wales?", "answer": "   ASK { ?p1 osm:has_name \"St. David's\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> ;         geo:hasGeometry ?p1geo. ?p1geo  geo:asWKT ?p1aswkt . <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wales>  geo:hasGeometry ?p2geo. ?p2geo geo:asWKT ?p2aswkt . ?p3 rdf:type osm:City;     geo:hasGeometry ?p3geo . ?p3geo geo:asWKT ?p3aswkt. FILTER (geof:sfWithin(?p1aswkt, ?p2aswkt)) . FILTER (geof:distance(?p1aswkt, ?p3aswkt, uom:metre) <= 2000). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/38.sparql", "number": 38, "question": "Is Alnwick Castle in Scotland?", "answer": "   ask {                                 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Alnwick_Castle> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.                         }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/39.sparql", "number": 39, "question": "Which colleges are in London?", "answer": "   select distinct ?p2 { ?p1 osm:has_name \"London\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> ;         geo:hasGeometry ?p1geo. ?p1geo  geo:asWKT ?p1aswkt . ?p2 a osm:College;     geo:hasGeometry ?p2geo . ?p2geo geo:asWKT ?p2aswkt. FILTER (geof:sfWithin(?p2aswkt, ?p1aswkt)) . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/40.sparql", "number": 40, "question": "How many districts does Northern Ireland have?", "answer": "   SELECT (count(distinct ?x)as ?total) WHERE {          ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_district_108552138>.          ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Northern_Ireland> . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/41.sparql", "number": 41, "question": "Which pubs are near Mercure Hotel in Glasgow", "answer": "   SELECT DISTINCT ?pub WHERE{        ?pub    a    osm:Pub ;                 geo:hasGeometry ?pubGeom .         ?pubGeom    geo:asWKT   ?pubWKT .         ?hotel  a    osm:Hotel ;                 osm:has_name   \"Mercure Hotel\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> ;                 geo:hasGeometry ?hotelGeom .         ?hotelGeom    geo:asWKT   ?hotelWKT .         ?instance   owl:sameAs  <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Glasgow> ;                     geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom .         ?instanceGeom   geo:asWKT   ?instanceWKT.         FILTER ( geof:sfContains(?instanceWKT, ?hotelWKT) && geof:distance(?hotelWKT, ?pubWKT, uom:metre) <= 1000)   }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/42.sparql", "number": 42, "question": "Is there a mountain within 20km of Cheshire?", "answer": "   ASK {  ?instance   owl:sameAs  <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Cheshire> ;     geo:hasGeometry ?chesGeom .            ?chesGeom geo:asWKT   ?chesWKT .             ?mount a osm:Peak;                 geo:hasGeometry ?mountGeom.             ?mountGeom geo:asWKT ?mountWKT.             FILTER (geof:distance(?chesWKT, ?mountWKT, uom:metre) <= 20000)      }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/43.sparql", "number": 43, "question": "Does London have a mountain?", "answer": "   ASK {         ?mountain rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_mountain_109359803>.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London> ?p ?mountain. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/44.sparql", "number": 44, "question": "Is Islington near Angel?", "answer": "   ASK { ?x owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Islington>; geo:hasGeometry ?iGeometry1. ?iGeometry1 geo:asWKT ?iWKT1. ?y owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Angel,_London>; geo:hasGeometry ?iGeometry2. ?iGeometry2 geo:asWKT ?iWKT2. FILTER(geof:distance(?iWKT1, ?iWKT2) < 10000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/45.sparql", "number": 45, "question": "Is there a car park near a bridge on river Exe?", "answer": "ASK\n{\nSERVICE <http://pyravlos1.di.uoa.gr:8890/sparql>\n{\n<http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/River_Exe> ?p ?o.\n?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_bridge_102898711>.\n?x rdf:label ?label.\n}\nSERVICE <http://pyravlos1.di.uoa.gr:8080/geoqa/Query>\n{\n?poi rdf:type osm:Parking .\n?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geom .\n\n?geom geo:asWKT ?wkt .\n?b osm:has_name ?label .\n?b geo:hasGeometry ?bGeom .\n?bGeom geo:asWKT ?bWKT .\nFILTER (geof:distance(?wkt, ?bWKT, <http://www.opengis.net/def/uom/OGC/1.0/metre>) < 500 ) .\n}\n}"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/46.sparql", "number": 46, "question": "Which medieval castles are in Scotland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x    where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_palace_103878066>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.   }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/47.sparql", "number": 47, "question": "Which bars are near Prince's street in Edinburgh?", "answer": "   SELECT ?poi WHERE {   <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Edinburgh> geo:hasGeometry ?e_geom .   ?e_geom geo:asWKT ?e_wkt.   ?ps <http://data.linkedeodata.eu/ontology#has_name> \"Princes Street\"^^xsd:string .   ?ps geo:hasGeometry ?ps_geom .   ?ps_geom geo:asWKT ?ps_wkt .   ?poi rdf:type osm:bar .   ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?poi_geom .   ?poi_geom geo:asWKT ?poi_wkt .   FILTER( geof:sfWithin(?ps_wkt, ?e_wkt) )   FILTER( geof:distance(?poi_wkt, ?ps_wkt, uom:metre) < 500 ) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/48.sparql", "number": 48, "question": "Which hotels are near Loch Ness?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?poi WHERE {   ?s osm:has_name \"Loch Ness\"^^xsd:string .   ?poi rdf:type osm:Hotel .   ?s geo:hasGeometry ?s_geom .   ?s_geom geo:asWKT ?s_wkt .   ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?poi_geom .   ?poi_geom geo:asWKT ?poi_wkt.   FILTER( geof:distance(?poi_wkt, ?s_wkt, uom:metre) < 500 ) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/49.sparql", "number": 49, "question": "Is Liverpool part of Scotland?", "answer": "   ASK {         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Liverpool> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/50.sparql", "number": 50, "question": "Which museums are within 3km of Saint George's hotel in London?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?poi WHERE { ?poi rdf:type osm:Museum. ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geom . ?geom geo:asWKT ?wkt . ?instance rdf:type osm:Hotel . ?instance osm:has_name \"Saint Georges Hotel\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> . ?instance geo:hasGeometry ?inGeom . ?inGeom geo:asWKT ?inWKT . FILTER (geof:distance(?wkt, ?inWKT, <http://www.opengis.net/def/uom/OGC/1.0/metre>) <= 3000 ) . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/51.sparql", "number": 51, "question": "How many rivers cross Edinburgh?", "answer": "   SELECT (count(distinct ?x)as ?total) WHERE {         ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.         ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Edinburgh>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/52.sparql", "number": 52, "question": "Which county is east of county Dorset?", "answer": "   select distinct ?county where {        <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Dorset> geo:hasGeometry ?geomLC.        ?geomLC geo:asWKT ?niWKT.        ?county  rdf:type  <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>;                        <http://www.opengis.net/ont/geosparql#hasGeometry> ?geomC.        ?geomC geo:asWKT ?cWKT.        FILTER(strdf:right(?cWKT, ?niWKT)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/53.sparql", "number": 53, "question": "In what county is Stonehenge located?", "answer": "SELECT ?c WHERE {\n\n        ?p1 osm:has_name \"Stonehenge\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> ;\n                geo:hasGeometry ?p1geo.\n        ?p1geo  geo:asWKT ?p1aswkt .\n\n        ?c rdf:type <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>;\n           geo:hasGeometry ?cgeo.\n        ?cgeo geo:asWKT ?caswkt.\n        FILTER (geof:sfWithin(?p1aswkt, ?caswkt)) .\n}"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/54.sparql", "number": 54, "question": "Is there a forest in county Cheshire?", "answer": "   ASK {          ?forest rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_forest_108438533>.          ?forest ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Cheshire>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/55.sparql", "number": 55, "question": "How many counties does the river Thames cross?", "answer": "   SELECT (count(distinct ?x)as ?total) WHERE {         ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_county_108546183>.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/River_Thames> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?x. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/56.sparql", "number": 56, "question": "Is there a river that crosses county Greater Manchester?", "answer": "   ASK {         ?river rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.         ?river ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Greater_Manchester>.    }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/57.sparql", "number": 57, "question": "Is there a museum at most 1km from Liverpool?", "answer": "   ASK { ?museum rdf:type osm:Museum . ?museum geo:hasGeometry ?geom . ?geom geo:asWKT ?wkt . <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Liverpool> geo:hasGeometry ?livGeom . ?livGeom geo:asWKT ?livWKT . FILTER (geof:distance(?wkt, ?livWKT, <http://www.opengis.net/def/uom/OGC/1.0/metre>) < 1000 ) . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/58.sparql", "number": 58, "question": "Which restaurants in London are near Kensington Palace?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?poi WHERE { ?poi rdf:type osm:Restaurant . ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geom . ?geom geo:asWKT ?wkt . ?instance rdf:type osm:Attraction . ?instance osm:has_name \"Kensington Palace\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> . ?instance geo:hasGeometry ?inGeom . ?inGeom geo:asWKT ?inWKT . FILTER (geof:distance(?wkt, ?inWKT, <http://www.opengis.net/def/uom/OGC/1.0/metre>) < 500 ) . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/59.sparql", "number": 59, "question": "Which provinces of Ireland have population over 2 million?", "answer": "select distinct ?x\nwhere {\n         ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_state_108654360>.\n         ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>.\n         ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasNumberOfPeople> ?o.\n         FILTER(?o > 2000000)\n}"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/60.sparql", "number": 60, "question": "Is the monument of the Great Fire of London east of King WIlliam Street?", "answer": "   ASK { ?poi rdf:type osm:Monument . ?poi osm:has_name \"The Great Fire\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> . ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geom . ?geom geo:asWKT ?wkt . ?road rdf:type osm:Residential . ?road osm:has_name \"King William Street\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> . ?road geo:hasGeometry ?roadGeom . ?roadGeom geo:asWKT ?roadWKT . FILTER (strdf:right(?wkt, ?roadWKT)) }         \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/61.sparql", "number": 61, "question": "Which city council includes Dublin?", "answer": "   select distinct ?o where {     <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Dublin> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/governmenttype> ?o.     FILTER CONTAINS(str(?o),\"City Council\") }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/62.sparql", "number": 62, "question": "Which are the non-metropolitan counties of England?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x where {          ?x   a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wikicat_Non-metropolitan_counties>.          ?x ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/63.sparql", "number": 63, "question": "Which are the main railway stations in Glasgow?", "answer": "   SELECT DISTINCT ?rs WHERE{              ?rs a    osm:Railway_Station ;             geo:hasGeometry ?rsGeom .         ?rsGeom geo:asWKT   ?rsWKT .          ?x owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Glasgow>;             geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom .         ?instanceGeom   geo:asWKT   ?instanceWKT.         FILTER geof:sfContains(?instanceWKT, ?rsWKT) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/64.sparql", "number": 64, "question": "What historical monuments are there in London?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 WHERE {         ?x1 a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_monument_108600443>.         ?x1 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/65.sparql", "number": 65, "question": "What is the area of county Cheshire?", "answer": "   select distinct ?area WHERE {         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Cheshire> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/areatotalkm> ?area. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/66.sparql", "number": 66, "question": "What is the length of river Thames?", "answer": "   SELECT ?length WHERE {         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/River_Thames> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasLength> ?length. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/67.sparql", "number": 67, "question": "How many rivers cross England's cities?", "answer": "   SELECT (COUNT(distinct ?x1) as ?num) WHERE {         ?x1 a osm:River.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England> geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT.         ?x3 a osm:City.        ?x3 geo:hasGeometry ?x3Geo.        ?x3Geo geo:asWKT ?x3WKT.         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?x3WKT, ?x2WKT)).         FILTER(geof:sfCrosses(?x1WKT, ?x3WKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/68.sparql", "number": 68, "question": "Is the City of London north of the Thames river?", "answer": "   ASK {     ?l owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>; geo:hasGeometry ?lGeom.          ?lGeom geo:asWKT ?lWKT.      ?river osm:has_name \"River Thames\"^^xsd:string; rdf:type osm:River; geo:hasGeometry ?iGeometry2.          ?iGeometry2 geo:asWKT ?iWKT2.        FILTER(strdf:above(?lWKT, ?iWKT2))  }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/69.sparql", "number": 69, "question": "Is there a castle in London near Trafalgar Square?", "answer": "   ASK {         ?x1 a osm:Castle.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         ?instance owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>; geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT.         ?x3 osm:has_name \"Trafalgar Square\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x3 geo:hasGeometry ?x3Geo.         ?x3Geo geo:asWKT ?x3WKT.         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)).         FILTER(geof:distance(?x1WKT, ?x3WKT, uom:metre) <= 500)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/70.sparql", "number": 70, "question": "Which counties of England border country Scotland?", "answer": "   select ?county where {        ?county  rdf:type  <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>;       geo:hasGeometry ?geomC.   ?geomC geo:asWKT ?cWKT.       <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland> geo:hasGeometry ?sGeom.      ?sGeom geo:asWKT ?sWKT.                  <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England> geo:hasGeometry ?eGeom.        ?sGeom geo:asWKT ?eWKT.        FILTER(geof:sfTouches(?sWKT, ?cWKT) && geof:sfWithin(?cWKT,?eWKT)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/71.sparql", "number": 71, "question": "Is there any airfield in Wellesbourne village in England?", "answer": "   select distinct ?airfield where {   ?airfield rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_airfield_102687992>.   ?airfield ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wellesbourne>.      <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wellesbourne> rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_village_108672738>;                 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn>+ ?o.       FILTER CONTAINS(str(?o),\"England\") }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/72.sparql", "number": 72, "question": "Is there an aerodrome in Essex?", "answer": "   select distinct ?airport where {          ?airport rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_airport_102692232>.          ?airport <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Essex> . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/73.sparql", "number": 73, "question": "Is Somerset west of Westmorland?", "answer": "   ASK { <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Somerset> geo:hasGeometry ?iGeometry1. ?iGeometry1 geo:asWKT ?iWKT1. ?y owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Westmorland>; geo:hasGeometry ?iGeometry2. ?iGeometry2 geo:asWKT ?iWKT2. FILTER(strdf:left(?iWKT1, ?iWKT2)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/74.sparql", "number": 74, "question": "How many cities does Merseyside have?", "answer": "   SELECT (COUNT(?x1) as ?num) WHERE {         ?x1 a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.         ?x1 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Merseyside>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/75.sparql", "number": 75, "question": "What historic buildings are in Buckinghamshire?", "answer": "   ASK  {   ?poi rdf:type osm:Archaeological .   ?poi geo:hasGeometry  ?poiGeom .   ?poiGeom  geo:asWKT ?poiWKT .   ?poi osm:has_name ?name .   <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Buckinghamshire> geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom .   ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT ?instanceWKT .   FILTER( geof:sfWithin(?poiWKT, ?instanceWKT) ) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/76.sparql", "number": 76, "question": "Is there a mountain in Merseyside?", "answer": "   ASK {         ?mountain rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_mountain_109359803>.         ?mountain ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Merseyside>.   }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/77.sparql", "number": 77, "question": "Does county Suffolk border county Durham?", "answer": "   ASK {       <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/County_Durham> geo:hasGeometry ?xGeom.        ?xGeom geo:asWKT ?xWKT.        <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Suffolk> geo:hasGeometry ?mGeom.        ?mGeom geo:asWKT ?mWKT.        FILTER(geof:sfTouches(?xWKT,?mWKT)) }  \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/78.sparql", "number": 78, "question": "Which restaurants are at most 500m from the University of Liverpool?", "answer": "   select distinct ?p2 WHERE { ?p1 osm:has_name \"University of Liverpool\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> ;       a osm:University ;       geo:hasGeometry ?p1geo. ?p1geo geo:asWKT ?p1aswkt. ?p2 rdf:type osm:Restaurant;        geo:hasGeometry ?p2geo . ?p2geo geo:asWKT ?p2aswkt. FILTER (geof:distance(?p1aswkt, ?p2aswkt, uom:metre) <= 500) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/79.sparql", "number": 79, "question": "Which parks are near Trafalgar Square?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 WHERE {         ?x1 a osm:Park.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         ?x2 osm:has_name \"Trafalgar Square\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x2 geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         FILTER(geof:distance(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT, uom:metre) <= 500)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/80.sparql", "number": 80, "question": "Which villages in Scotland have a population of less than 500 people?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 WHERE {         ?x1 a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_village_108672738>.         ?x1 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.         ?x1 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/population> ?x1population.         FILTER(xsd:integer(?x1population) < 500). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/81.sparql", "number": 81, "question": "Is there a Modern Art Museum in London?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?x WHERE {         ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_museum_103800563>.         ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>.         ?x rdfs:label ?label         FILTER regex(str(?label), \"Modern Art\", \"i\") }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/82.sparql", "number": 82, "question": "Through which cities does River Thames flow?", "answer": "   select distinct ?owhere {        <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/River_Thames> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?o.         ?o rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/83.sparql", "number": 83, "question": "Is there a train station in Dublin?", "answer": "   ASK {         ?x1 a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_railway_station_104049098>.         ?x1 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Dublin>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/84.sparql", "number": 84, "question": "Is there a forest in Lancashire north of Burnley?", "answer": "   ASK {         ?x1 a osm:Forest.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Lancashire> geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Burnley> geo:hasGeometry ?x3Geo.         ?x3Geo geo:asWKT ?x3WKT.         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)).         FILTER(strdf:above(?x1WKT, ?x3WKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/85.sparql", "number": 85, "question": "Is there a county of England that borders the Isle of Wight?", "answer": "   ASK {   ?county rdf:type <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>; geo:hasGeometry ?cGeom.            ?cGeom geo:asWKT ?cWKT.           <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England> geo:hasGeometry ?eGeom.            ?eGeom geo:asWKT ?eWKT.                <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Isle_of_Wight> geo:hasGeometry ?iwGeom.            ?iwGeom geo:asWKT ?iwWKT.           FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?cWKT,?eWKT))             FILTER(geof:sfTouches(?eWKT,?iwWKT)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/86.sparql", "number": 86, "question": "Is there a church in the county of Greater Manchester dedicated to St. Patrick?", "answer": "   ASK {          ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_church_103028079>.          ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Greater_Manchester>.          ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/dedication> ?property.          FILTER(CONTAINS(?property,\"Patrick\")) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/87.sparql", "number": 87, "question": "Which pubs in Liverpool are at most 2km from Anfield stadium?", "answer": "   select distinct ?pubs where {                            ?pubs rdf:type osm:Pub;                                              geo:hasGeometry ?pGeom.                             ?pGeom geo:asWKT ?pWKT.                                                 ?ast owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Anfield>;                                 geo:hasGeometry ?astGeom.                            ?astGeom geo:asWKT ?astWKT.                                <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Liverpool> geo:hasGeometry ?lGeom.                       ?lGeom geo:asWKT ?lWKT.               FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?astWKT, ?lWKT) && geof:distance(?pWKT, ?astWKT, uom:metre) <= 2000) }   \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/88.sparql", "number": 88, "question": "Which pubs in Liverpool are near Anfield stadium?", "answer": "   select distinct ?pubs where {                            ?pubs rdf:type osm:Pub;                                              geo:hasGeometry ?pGeom.                             ?pGeom geo:asWKT ?pWKT.                                                 ?ast owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Anfield>;                                          geo:hasGeometry ?astGeom.                                 ?astGeom geo:asWKT ?astWKT.                                 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Liverpool> geo:hasGeometry ?lGeom.                                 ?lGeom geo:asWKT ?lWKT.                                                         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?astWKT, ?lWKT) && geof:distance(?pWKT, ?astWKT, uom:metre) <= 1000)  }   \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/89.sparql", "number": 89, "question": "Which hotels are in England's capital?", "answer": "   select distinct ?hotel where {          ?hotel rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_hotel_103542333> .          ?hotel <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?y .          <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasCapital> ?y . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/90.sparql", "number": 90, "question": "Which theaters are near Trafalgar Square?", "answer": "   SELECT  ?t  where { ?x osm:has_name  \"Trafalgar Square\"^^xsd:string;             rdf:type osm:Attraction.  ?x geo:hasGeometry ?geo . ?geo geo:asWKT ?w . ?t rdf:type osm:Theatre .  ?t geo:hasGeometry ?geo2 . ?geo2 geo:asWKT ?w2 . filter(geof:distance(?w,?w2, uom:metre) < 1000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/91.sparql", "number": 91, "question": "Through which cities does River Thames flow?", "answer": "   select distinct ?owhere {        <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/River_Thames> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?o.         ?o rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/92.sparql", "number": 92, "question": "Which rivers are in Great Britain?", "answer": "   select distinct ?rivers where {         {            ?rivers rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.  ?rivers <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.  } UNION   {   ?rivers rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.   ?rivers <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.   } UNION    {     ?rivers rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.    ?rivers <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wales>.    }  }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/93.sparql", "number": 93, "question": "Which airports are in the city of Salford?", "answer": "   select ?airports where {           ?airports rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_airport_102692232>.           ?airports ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/City_of_Salford>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/94.sparql", "number": 94, "question": "Where is a car park near Big Ben?", "answer": "   SELECT  distinct  ?w2 WHERE      {        ?poi osm:has_name   \"Big Ben\"^^xsd:string.          ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geo .       ?geo geo:asWKT ?w .       ?div rdf:type osm:Parking.           ?div geo:hasGeometry ?geo2 .       ?geo2 geo:asWKT ?w2 .  filter(geof:distance(?w,?w2, uom:metre) < 100)  }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/95.sparql", "number": 95, "question": "Is there a river that crosses Manchester?", "answer": "   ASK where {   ?river rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.     ?river ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Manchester>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/96.sparql", "number": 96, "question": "Which Scottish counties border England?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 {         ?x1 a <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1 geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland> geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England> geo:hasGeometry ?x3Geo.         ?x3Geo geo:asWKT ?x3WKT.         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)).         FILTER(geof:sfTouches(?x1WKT, ?x3WKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/97.sparql", "number": 97, "question": "Is there a car park at most 1km from Waterloo Bridge?", "answer": "   ASK WHERE {   ?entity osm:has_osm_id ?id;           osm:has_name \"Waterloo Bridge\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>;           geo:hasGeometry ?geomWaterloo.    ?geomWaterloo geo:asWKT ?waterloogeomWKT.    ?park rdf:type osm:Parking;           geo:hasGeometry ?parkGeom.    ?parkGeom geo:asWKT ?parkGeomWKT.   BIND (geof:buffer(?waterloogeomWKT, 1000, uom:metre) as ?waterlooEnv).   FILTER (geof:sfWithin(?parkGeomWKT, ?waterlooEnv)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/98.sparql", "number": 98, "question": "Where is Trafalgar Square located?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1WKT {         ?x1 osm:has_name \"Trafalgar Square\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/99.sparql", "number": 99, "question": "Is the Castle of Edinburgh less than 2km away from Calton Hill?", "answer": "   ASK {         ?x1 osm:has_name \"Calton Hill\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.                  ?x2 osm:has_name \"Edinburgh Castle\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x2 geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.                  FILTER(geof:distance(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT, uom:metre) < 2000). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/100.sparql", "number": 100, "question": "How many pharmacies are in 200 meter radius of High Street in Oxford?", "answer": "   SELECT (COUNT(DISTINCT ?poi) as ?totalPharmacies) WHERE   { ?poi      rdf:type         osm:Pharmacy ;                   geo:hasGeometry  ?poiGeom .         ?poiGeom  geo:asWKT        ?poiWKT .         ?instance  osm:has_name \"High Street\"^^xsd:string;                   geo:hasGeometry  ?instanceGeom .         ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT        ?instanceWKT.         FILTER( geof:distance(?instanceWKT, ?poiWKT, uom:metre) < 200)     }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/101.sparql", "number": 101, "question": "Which restaurants are near Edinburgh Castle?", "answer": "   SELECT ?poi WHERE{ ?city geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom;    osm:has_name \"Edinburgh Castle\"^^xsd:string;       a osm:Castle.    ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT        ?instanceWKT.    ?poi rdf:type osm:Restaurant ;     geo:hasGeometry ?poiGeom . ?poiGeom  geo:asWKT        ?poiWKT .   FILTER (geof:distance(?instanceWKT, ?poiWKT, uom:metre) < 500) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/102.sparql", "number": 102, "question": "Which hotels are near Big Ben?", "answer": "   SELECT ?poi WHERE{ ?city geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom;      osm:has_name \"Big Ben\"^^xsd:string .      ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT        ?instanceWKT.      ?poi rdf:type osm:Hotel ;             geo:hasGeometry ?poiGeom .?poiGeom  geo:asWKT        ?poiWKT .     FILTER (geof:distance(?instanceWKT, ?poiWKT, uom:metre) < 1000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/103.sparql", "number": 103, "question": "Which airports are in Ireland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?airport where {        ?airport rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_airport_102692232>.        ?airport <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/104.sparql", "number": 104, "question": "Which hospitals are close to Stirling Castle?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?x2 WHERE {         ?x1 osm:has_name \"Stirling Castle\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         ?x2 a osm:Hospital.         ?x2 geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         FILTER(geof:distance(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT, uom:metre) < 500). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/105.sparql", "number": 105, "question": "Which airports are in London?", "answer": "   select distinct ?airport where {         ?airport rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_airport_102692232>.         ?airport <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London> }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/106.sparql", "number": 106, "question": "Which universities are in England?", "answer": "   select distinct ?university where {          ?university rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_university_108286569>.           ?university <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/107.sparql", "number": 107, "question": "Which mountains are in Scotland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?mountains where {         ?mountains rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_mountain_109359803>.         ?mountains <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/108.sparql", "number": 108, "question": "Where is Elizabeth Tower located?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1WKT WHERE {         ?x1 osm:has_name \"Elizabeth Tower\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/109.sparql", "number": 109, "question": "Which pubs in Manchester are near the Old Trafford stadium?", "answer": "   SELECT  distinct ?div WHERE      {        ?poi osm:has_name    \"Old Trafford\"^^xsd:string.          ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geo .       ?geo geo:asWKT ?w .       ?poi rdf:type osm:Stadium .      ?div rdf:type osm:Pub.           ?div geo:hasGeometry ?geo2 .       ?geo2 geo:asWKT ?w2 .   filter(geof:distance(?w,?w2, uom:metre) < 500)   }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/110.sparql", "number": 110, "question": "Which rivers cross Derry?", "answer": "   select ?river where {          ?river rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.          ?river ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Derry>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/111.sparql", "number": 111, "question": "Which is the total area of Northern Ireland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?area {   <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Northern_Ireland> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/areakm> ?area. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/112.sparql", "number": 112, "question": "Where is Emirates Stadium located?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1WKT WHERE {         ?x1 osm:has_name \"Emirates Stadium\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/113.sparql", "number": 113, "question": "Which castles are in the Highland council area of Scotland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?castles where {     ?castles rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_palace_103878066>.          ?castles <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn>  <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Highland_(council_area)>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/114.sparql", "number": 114, "question": "How many are the counties of England?", "answer": "   SELECT (COUNT(?x1) AS ?num) WHERE {         ?x1 a <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>.        ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England> geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/115.sparql", "number": 115, "question": "Is there a national park near York?", "answer": "   ASK   {           ?park          rdf:type             osm:Park ;                       geo:hasGeometry  ?parkGeom .             ?parkGeom  geo:asWKT            ?parkWKT .              <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/York>       geo:hasGeometry  ?yorkGeom .             ?yorkGeom       geo:asWKT            ?yorkWKT . FILTER (geof:distance(?parkWKT, ?yorkWKT, uom:metre) < 5000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/116.sparql", "number": 116, "question": "Which cafes in Manchester are near Piccadilly Gardens?", "answer": "   Select distinct ?cafe WHERE { ?cafe a osm:Cafe ; geo:hasGeometry ?cafeGeo . ?cafeGeo geo:asWKT ?cafeWKT . <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Manchester> geo:hasGeometry ?ManchesterGeo . ?ManchesterGeo geo:asWKT ?ManchesterWKT . ?Piccadilly osm:has_name ?l; geo:hasGeometry ?PiccadillyGeo; rdf:type osm:Park. ?PiccadillyGeo geo:asWKT ?PiccadillyWKT . filter( str(?l)=\"Piccadilly Gardens\"). filter(geof:sfContains(?ManchesterWKT, ?PiccadillyWKT)). filter (geof:distance(?cafeWKT, ?PiccadillyWKT, uom:metre) <= 1000). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/117.sparql", "number": 117, "question": "Which hotels in Manchester are near Wharfside Way?", "answer": "   Select ?hotel WHERE { ?hotel a osm:Hotel ; geo:hasGeometry ?hoteleo . ?hotelGeo geo:asWKT ?hotelWKT . <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Manchester> geo:hasGeometry ?ManchesterGeo . ?ManchesterGeo geo:asWKT ?ManchesterWKT . ?Wharfside osm:has_name ?l; geo:hasGeometry ?WharfsideGeo . ?WharfsideGeo geo:asWKT ?WharfsideWKT .  filter(geof:sfContains(?ManchesterWKT, ?hotelWKT)). filter (geof:distance(?hotelWKT, ?WharfsideWKT, uom:metre) < 1000). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/118.sparql", "number": 118, "question": "Which county is west of South Yorkshire?", "answer": "   select distinct ?counties where { ?counties rdf:type <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>; geo:hasGeometry ?cGeom.                 ?cGeom geo:asWKT ?cWKT.        ?sy owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/South_Yorkshire>; geo:hasGeometry ?syGeom.  ?syGeom geo:asWKT ?syWKT.       FILTER(strdf:left(?cWKT, ?iWKT))  }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/119.sparql", "number": 119, "question": "Where can I find a car park in Bristol?", "answer": "   Select distinct ?parking WHERE { ?parking a osm:Parking ; geo:hasGeometry ?parkingGeo . ?parkingGeo geo:asWKT ?parkingWKT . <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Bristol> geo:hasGeometry ?BristolGeo . ?BristolGeo geo:asWKT ?BristolWKT . filter(geof:sfContains(?BristolWKT, ?parkingWKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/120.sparql", "number": 120, "question": "Which villages are in Herefordshire?", "answer": "   select ?villeges  where {              ?villeges rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_village_108672738>.              ?villeges <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Herefordshire>. } \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/121.sparql", "number": 121, "question": "How many mountains are there in Scotland?", "answer": "   select (count(distinct ?x) as ?totalMountain) where {             ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_mountain_109359803>.             ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/122.sparql", "number": 122, "question": "Which city is southeast of Salford?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 WHERE {         ?x1 a osm:City.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Salford> geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         FILTER(strdf:below(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)).         FILTER(strdf:left(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/123.sparql", "number": 123, "question": "Which university colleges are in Scotland?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 WHERE {         ?x1 a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_college_108278324>.         ?x1 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/124.sparql", "number": 124, "question": "In which city is Big Ben located?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 WHERE {         ?x1 a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Big_Ben> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?x1. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/125.sparql", "number": 125, "question": "Does the district of Coleraine border Belfast?", "answer": "   ASK {         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Coleraine> geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Belfast> geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         FILTER(geof:sfTouches(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/126.sparql", "number": 126, "question": "Which forests are in Northern Ireland?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 WHERE {         ?x1 a osm:Forest.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.        ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Northern_Ireland> geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/127.sparql", "number": 127, "question": "Is there a park in Dublin near Grafton Street?", "answer": "   ASK {         ?x1 a osm:Park.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         ?x2 osm:has_name \"Grafton Street\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x2 geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Dublin> geo:hasGeometry ?x3Geo.         ?x3Geo geo:asWKT ?x3WKT.         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?x1WKT, ?x3WKT)).         FILTER(geof:distance(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT, uom:metre) < 1000). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/128.sparql", "number": 128, "question": "Is Trafalgar square located in London?", "answer": "   ASK {        <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Trafalgar_Square> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/129.sparql", "number": 129, "question": "How many parks are there in Northampton?", "answer": "   select (count(distinct ?x) as ?totalPark) where {                      ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_park_108615149>.              ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Northampton>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/130.sparql", "number": 130, "question": "Which aerodrome is in Essex?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x where {                      ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_airport_102692232>.              ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Essex>.  } \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/131.sparql", "number": 131, "question": "Is Edinburgh west of Glasgow?", "answer": "   ASK { <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Edinburgh> geo:hasGeometry ?iGeometry1. ?iGeometry1 geo:asWKT ?iWKT1. ?y owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Glasgow>; geo:hasGeometry ?iGeometry2. ?iGeometry2 geo:asWKT ?iWKT2. FILTER(strdf:left(?iWKT1, ?iWKT2)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/132.sparql", "number": 132, "question": "Is there an airport in Dublin?", "answer": "   ASK {           ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_airport_102692232>.           ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Dublin>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/133.sparql", "number": 133, "question": "Which Greek restaurants in London are near Wembley stadium?", "answer": "   SELECT  ?poi ?name WHERE {   ?poi rdf:type osm:Restaurant .   ?poi geo:hasGeometry  ?poiGeom .   ?poiGeom  geo:asWKT ?poiWKT .   ?poi osm:has_name ?name .   ?instance owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London> .   ?instance geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom .   ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT ?instanceWKT .   FILTER( geof:sfWithin(?poiWKT, ?instanceWKT) )   FILTER( CONTAINS(LCASE(?name), \"greek\") ) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/134.sparql", "number": 134, "question": "Which counties of Ireland does River Shannon cross?", "answer": "   select distinct ?county where {       ?x owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>; geo:hasGeometry ?geomLC.      ?geomLC geo:asWKT ?niWKT.    ?county  rdf:type  <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OSI_County_Council>;            <http://www.opengis.net/ont/geosparql#hasGeometry> ?geomC.        ?geomC geo:asWKT ?cWKT.        ?river  rdf:type  osm:River;                 osm:has_name \"River Shannon\"^^xsd:string;                        geo:hasGeometry ?geomR.        ?geomR geo:asWKT ?rWKT.        FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?cWKT, ?niWKT))        FILTER(geof:sfCrosses(?rWKT, ?cWKT)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/135.sparql", "number": 135, "question": "Which restaurants are near Baker Street in London?", "answer": "   SELECT  distinct ?p2 WHERE {          ?l owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>; geo:hasGeometry ?lGeom.         ?lGeom geo:asWKT ?lWKT.   ?p1 osm:has_name \"Baker Street\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> ;                   geo:hasGeometry  ?p1geo .         ?p1geo  geo:asWKT ?p1aswkt.          ?p2 rdf:type osm:Restaurant;                geo:hasGeometry ?p2geo .         ?p2geo geo:asWKT ?p2aswkt. FILTER (geof:sfWithin(?p1aswkt,?lWKT) && geof:distance(?p1aswkt, ?p2aswkt, uom:metre) < 500) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/136.sparql", "number": 136, "question": "Which countries border Wales?", "answer": "   select distinct ?country where {            ?country rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_country_108544813>.            <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wales> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasNeighbor> ?country. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/137.sparql", "number": 137, "question": "Is England part of the United Kingdom ?", "answer": "   ASK {         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England> geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/United_Kingdom> geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WK.         FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/138.sparql", "number": 138, "question": "How many county councils are there in Ireland?", "answer": "SELECT (count(distinct ?county)as ?total)\nWHERE {\n        <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>   geo:hasGeometry ?irelandGeom.\n\n  ?irelandGeom geo:asWKT ?irelandGeomWKT.\n\n  ?county gadmOnt:hasName ?countyName;\n          geo:hasGeometry ?countyGeom.\n\n   ?countyGeom geo:asWKT ?countyGeomWKT.\n\n   FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?countyGeomWKT, ?irelandGeomWKT))\n}"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/139.sparql", "number": 139, "question": "Which restaurants are near Stonehenge?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 WHERE {         ?x1 a osm:Restaurant.         ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1Geo.         ?x1Geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.         ?x2 osm:has_name \"Stonehenge\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.         ?x2 geo:hasGeometry ?x2Geo.         ?x2Geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.         FILTER(geof:distance(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT, uom:metre) < 1000). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/140.sparql", "number": 140, "question": "What tourist attractions are there in Belfast, Northern Ireland?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?p2  WHERE {  <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Northern_Ireland> geo:hasGeometry ?p0geo. ?p0geo  geo:asWKT ?p0aswkt . ?bl owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Belfast>; geo:hasGeometry ?p1geo. ?p1geo  geo:asWKT ?p1aswkt . ?p2 rdf:type osm:Attraction;     geo:hasGeometry ?p2geo. ?p2geo geo:asWKT ?p2aswkt . FILTER (geof:sfWithin(?p2aswkt, ?p1aswkt) && geof:sfWithin(?p1aswkt, ?p0aswkt)  )  }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/141.sparql", "number": 141, "question": "Which rivers in Scotland have more than 100 km length?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                     ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.              ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.              ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasLength> ?property.              FILTER(?property > \"100000\"^^<http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/m>). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/142.sparql", "number": 142, "question": "Which are the districts of county Chesire?", "answer": "   select distinct ?districts where {          ?districts ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wikicat_Districts_of_Cheshire>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/143.sparql", "number": 143, "question": "Where is Tower Bridge located?", "answer": "   SELECT ?xWKT WHERE {         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Tower_Bridge> geo:hasGeometry ?xgeo.         ?xgeo geo:asWKT ?xWKT. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/144.sparql", "number": 144, "question": "Is London south of Manchester?", "answer": "   ASK {        <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/geoentity_City_of_London_2643744> geo:hasGeometry ?xGeom.       ?xGeom geo:asWKT ?xWKT.        <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Manchester> geo:hasGeometry ?mGeom.      ?mGeom geo:asWKT ?mWKT.        FILTER(strdf:below(?xWKT,?mWKT)) }  \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/145.sparql", "number": 145, "question": "Are there any lakes in Scotland?", "answer": "   ASK {                     ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_lake_109328904>.              ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.         }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/146.sparql", "number": 146, "question": "Which counties border county Donegal to the south?", "answer": "   SELECT ?x1 WHERE {     ?x1 a <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_County>.     ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1geo.     ?x1geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.     <https://yago-knowledge.org/resource/County_Donegal> geo:hasGeometry ?x2geo.     ?x2geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.     FILTER(strdf:below(?x1WKT,?x2WKT)).     FILTER(geof:sfTouches(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT)). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/147.sparql", "number": 147, "question": "Is there a forest near Manchester?", "answer": "   ASK  {       ?forest      rdf:type         <http://www.app-lab.eu/osm/ontology#forest> ;                   geo:hasGeometry  ?forestGeom .         ?forestGeom  geo:asWKT        ?forestWKT .         ?Manchester  owl:sameAs      <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Manchester> ;                   geo:hasGeometry  ?ManchesterGeom .         ?Manchestereom                   geo:asWKT        ?ManchesterWKT . FILTER (geof:distance(?forestWKT, ?ManchesterWKT, uom:metre) < 5000) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/148.sparql", "number": 148, "question": "Is the Tower of London near river Thames?", "answer": "   ASK {     ?x1 osm:has_name \"Tower of London\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.     ?x1 geo:hasGeometry ?x1geo.     ?x1geo geo:asWKT ?x1WKT.     ?x2 osm:has_name \"Thames\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string>.     ?x2 geo:hasGeometry ?x2geo.     ?x2geo geo:asWKT ?x2WKT.     FILTER(geof:distance(?x1WKT, ?x2WKT, uom:metre) < 50000). }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/149.sparql", "number": 149, "question": "Does Hammersmith Bridge connect Hammersmith with Barnes?", "answer": "   ASK { ?poi rdf:type osm:Bridge . ?poi osm:has_name \"Hammersmith Bridge\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> . ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geom . ?geom geo:asWKT ?wkt . ?ham owl:sameAS <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Hammersmith> . ?ham geo:hasGeometry ?hamGeom . ?hamGeom geo:asWKT ?hamWKT . ?bar owl:sameAS <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Barnes,_London> . ?bar geo:hasGeometry ?barGeom . ?barGeom geo:asWKT ?barWKT . FILTER (geof:sfTouches(?hamWKT, ?wkt)) FILTER (geof:sfTouches(?barWKT, ?wkt)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/150.sparql", "number": 150, "question": "In which part of England is Liverpool located?", "answer": "   not available\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/151.sparql", "number": 151, "question": "Which rivers discharge into the Solway Firth?", "answer": "   select distinct ?river where {          ?river rdf:type  <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.          ?river ?p <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Solway_Firth>. }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/152.sparql", "number": 152, "question": "Which art museums are at most 1km from Charlotte Square in Edinburgh?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?poi WHERE { ?poi rdf:type osm:Museum. ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geom . ?geom geo:asWKT ?wkt . ?instance osm:has_name \"Charlotte Square\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> . ?instance geo:hasGeometry ?inGeom . ?inGeom geo:asWKT ?inWKT . FILTER (geof:distance(?wkt, ?inWKT, <http://www.opengis.net/def/uom/OGC/1.0/metre>) <= 1000 ) . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/153.sparql", "number": 153, "question": "Which rivers cross county Cheshire?", "answer": "   select distinct ?river where {     ?river rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.         ?river <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Cheshire> }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/154.sparql", "number": 154, "question": "Where can I find a car park in Exeter?", "answer": "   SELECT distinct ?poi WHERE { ?poi rdf:type osm:Parking . ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?poiGeom . ?poiGeom geo:asWKT ?poiWKT . ?city owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Exeter> . ?city geo:hasGeometry ?cityGeom . ?cityGeom geo:asWKT ?cityWKT . FILTER (geof:sfWithin(?poiWKT, ?cityWKT)) }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/155.sparql", "number": 155, "question": "Which is the highest mountain in Ireland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_mountain_109359803>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/elevationm>  ?property.                                 } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/156.sparql", "number": 156, "question": "Where is the closest market to Elephant and Castle underground station?", "answer": "   SELECT ?poiWKT ?poi (geof:distance(?poiWKT, ?instanceWKT, uom:metre) as ?res) WHERE   { SERVICE <http://pyravlos2.di.uoa.gr:8080/geoqa/Query>       { ?city geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom;                    osm:has_name \"Elephant and Castle\"^^xsd:string;                    a osm:Railway_Station.         ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT        ?instanceWKT.         ?poi rdf:type osm:Supermarket ;              geo:hasGeometry ?poiGeom .         ?poiGeom  geo:asWKT        ?poiWKT .              FILTER(geof:distance(?poiWKT, ?instanceWKT, uom:metre) < 1000)       }   } ORDER BY geof:distance(?poiWKT, ?instanceWKT, uom:metre) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/157.sparql", "number": 157, "question": "What is the name of Britain's longest river?", "answer": "   select distinct ?name ?property where  {     {               ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.               ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.               ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasLength> ?property.               ?x rdfs:label ?name.              } UNION              {               ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.               ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wales>.               ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasLength> ?property.               ?x rdfs:label ?name.              } UNION              {               ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.               ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.               ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasLength> ?property.               ?x rdfs:label ?name.              } } ORDER BY DESC(xsd:integer(str(?property))) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/158.sparql", "number": 158, "question": "Which cities in England have at least 2 castles?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x  where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.                                 ?y rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_palace_103878066>.                                  ?y <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?x.                                 } GROUP BY ?x HAVING (count(DISTINCT ?y) > 1)\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/159.sparql", "number": 159, "question": "Which is the biggest county council in the Republic of Ireland?", "answer": "   SELECT ?countyName WHERE {         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>   geo:hasGeometry ?irelandGeom.   ?irelandGeom geo:asWKT ?irelandGeomWKT.   ?county gadmOnt:hasName ?countyName;           geo:hasGeometry ?countyGeom.    ?countyGeom geo:asWKT ?countyGeomWKT.    FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?countyGeomWKT, ?irelandGeomWKT)) } ORDER BY ASC (strdf:area(?countyGeomWKT)) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/160.sparql", "number": 160, "question": "Which football stadium has the biggest capacity in Ireland?", "answer": "select distinct ?x\nwhere {\n          ?x a <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wikicat_Association_football_venues_in_the_Republic_of_Ireland>.\n \n          ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/seatingcapacity> ?o.\n} ORDER BY DESC(xsd:integer(?o)) LIMIT 1"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/161.sparql", "number": 161, "question": "Which site of Manchester is the most popular?", "answer": "SELECT  ?site ?sitename ?visitors\nWHERE\n  { SERVICE <http://pyravlos1.di.uoa.gr:8080/geoqa/Query> {\n            ?manchester owl:sameAs <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Manchester> ;\n               geo:hasGeometry [ geo:asWKT ?manchesterWKT ] .\n                    {\n                        { ?site a osm:Attraction . }\n                            UNION\n                        { ?site a osm:Museum . }\n                    }\n                ?site  owl:sameAs ?link ;\n                  osm:has_name ?sitename ;\n                  geo:hasGeometry [ geo:asWKT ?siteWKT ] .\n            FILTER(geof:sfWithin(?siteWKT, ?manchesterWKT)) .\n        }\n        SERVICE <http://pyravlos1.di.uoa.gr:8890/sparql> {\n            ?link <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/visitors> ?visitors  .\n        }\n}\nORDER BY DESC(?visitors)\nLIMIT 1"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/162.sparql", "number": 162, "question": "Which is the oldest bridge of London?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_bridge_102898711>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wasCreatedOnDate>  ?property.                                 } ORDER BY ?property LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/163.sparql", "number": 163, "question": "Where is the nearest gas station to St. Peter's Square in Manchester?", "answer": "   SELECT ?p3 WHERE {  ?p1 osm:has_name \"St. Peter's Square\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> ;         geo:hasGeometry ?p1geo. ?p1geo  geo:asWKT ?p1aswkt . <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Manchester>         geo:hasGeometry ?p2geo. ?p2geo geo:asWKT ?p2aswkt . ?p3 rdf:type osm:Fuel;     osm:has_name ?p3name;     geo:hasGeometry ?p3geo . ?p3geo geo:asWKT ?p3aswkt. FILTER (geof:sfWithin(?p1aswkt, ?p2aswkt)) . BIND(geof:distance(?p1aswkt, ?p3aswkt, uom:metre) as ?distance) } ORDER BY ?distance LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/164.sparql", "number": 164, "question": "Which city in Scotland has the largest population?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/populationtotal>  ?property.                                 } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/165.sparql", "number": 165, "question": "Which cities or towns of the United Kingdom have a university?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x where {                                { ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/United_Kingdom>.                                 ?z rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_university_108286569>.                                 ?z <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?x                               }                               UNION                               {                                 ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_town_108665504>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/United_Kingdom>.                                                                ?z rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_university_108286569>.                                                               ?z <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?x                               } }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/166.sparql", "number": 166, "question": "What is the elevation of the most elevated spot in county Down?", "answer": "   select distinct ?property where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_mountain_109359803>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/County_Down>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/elevationm> ?property } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/167.sparql", "number": 167, "question": "Which is the largest county of England?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_county_108546183>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/areatotalkm> ?property                    } ORDER BY DESC(xsd:integer(?property)) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/168.sparql", "number": 168, "question": "What is the longest river in England and Wales?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                { ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasLength> ?property                               }                               UNION                               {                                 ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wales>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasLength> ?property                               }                               } ORDER BY DESC(xsd:integer(?property)) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/169.sparql", "number": 169, "question": "What is the most populated city in the United Kingdom except London?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                   {            ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasNumberOfPeople> ?property. ?x rdfs:label ?name.                                               FILTER(!CONTAINS(str(?name),\"London\"))                                  } UNION                                     {   ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.   ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.   ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasNumberOfPeople> ?property                                  } UNION                                      {     ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.    ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wales>.   ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasNumberOfPeople> ?property                                   } UNION                                     {    ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.   ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Northern_Ireland>. ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasNumberOfPeople> ?property                                  } } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/170.sparql", "number": 170, "question": "Which city in Scotland has the largest population?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                    ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.   ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.   ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasNumberOfPeople> ?property                           } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/171.sparql", "number": 171, "question": "Which city of England is nearest to London?", "answer": "   SELECT ?city  (geof:distance(?LondonWKT, ?cityWKT, uom:metre) as ?distance)  WHERE {    ?city a osm:City ; geo:hasGeometry ?cityGeo . ?cityGeo geo:asWKT ?cityWKT .     ?London a osm:City ;     osm:has_name  ?l2 ; geo:hasGeometry ?LondonGeo . ?LondonGeo geo:asWKT ?LondonWKT . filter( str(?l2)=\"London\"). filter(?city != ?London). } ORDER BY ASC(?distance) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/172.sparql", "number": 172, "question": "Is there a river in Ireland that crosses more than 3 cities?", "answer": "   ASK { { select distinct ?x  where {                             ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.                          ?y rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.                             ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>.                             ?y <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>.      ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?y.  } GROUP BY(?x) HAVING(count(?y)>3) } }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/173.sparql", "number": 173, "question": "Which is the largest royal borough of London?", "answer": "SELECT ?x\nWHERE {\n        ?x rdf:type <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_LondonBoroughWard>;   geo:hasGeometry ?Geom.\n\n  ?Geom geo:asWKT ?GeomWKT.\n} ORDER BY ASC (strdf:area(?GeomWKT)) LIMIT 1"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/174.sparql", "number": 174, "question": "Which river crosses the most cities in England?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x where {                                                                        ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.             ?y rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.                                                                            ?y <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.                                     ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?y. } GROUP BY ?x ORDER BY DESC(COUNT(distinct ?y)) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/175.sparql", "number": 175, "question": "Which is the largest lake by area in Great Britain?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                   {            ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_lake_109328904>.  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/area> ?property                                  } UNION                                     {   ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_lake_109328904>.   ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.   ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/areae> ?property                                  } UNION                                      {     ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_lake_109328904>.    ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wales>.   ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/area> ?property                                   }                                } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/176.sparql", "number": 176, "question": "Does Everton FC plays in Liverpool?", "answer": "ASK {\n        <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Everton_F.C.> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/ground> ?o.\n        FILTER(contains(?o,\"Liverpool\"))\n}"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/177.sparql", "number": 177, "question": "Which is the largest city of Ireland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {             ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.                                                                            ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>.                                     ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/areatotalkm> ?property             } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/178.sparql", "number": 178, "question": "Which car park is closest to a bridge on river Exe?", "answer": "Select ?poi\n{\nSERVICE <http://pyravlos1.di.uoa.gr:8890/sparql>\n{\n<http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/River_Exe> ?p ?o.\n?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_bridge_102898711>.\n?x rdf:label ?label.\n}\nSERVICE <http://pyravlos1.di.uoa.gr:8080/geoqa/Query>\n{\n?poi rdf:type osm:Parking .\n?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geom .\n\n?geom geo:asWKT ?wkt .\n?b osm:has_name ?label .\n?b geo:hasGeometry ?bGeom .\n?bGeom geo:asWKT ?bWKT .\nFILTER (geof:distance(?wkt, ?bWKT, <http://www.opengis.net/def/uom/OGC/1.0/metre>) < 500 ) .\n}\n} ORDER BY DESC(geof:distance(?wkt, ?bWKT, <http://www.opengis.net/def/uom/OGC/1.0/metre>) < 500) LIMIT 1"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/179.sparql", "number": 179, "question": "What is the most densely populated city in Ireland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                                                                                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.                                                                            ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>.               ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasPopulationDensity> ?property                 } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/180.sparql", "number": 180, "question": "Is Glasgow the largest city of Scotland in terms of population?", "answer": "   select (?property1 > ?property) where {        ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.                                     ?x rdfs:label ?xname.                                                                         ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasNumberOfPeople> ?property1.                                      ?y rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.                                     ?y <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.                                     ?y <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasNumberOfPeople> ?property.                                     ?y rdfs:label ?yname.                                      FILTER(CONTAINS(?xname,\"Glasgow\") && !CONTAINS(?yname,\"Glasgow\"))                               }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/181.sparql", "number": 181, "question": "Does England have more counties than Ireland?", "answer": "   select (COUNT(DISTINCT ?x) > COUNT(DISTINCT ?y)) {                {   select ?x  {    ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_county_108546183>.                                    ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.                                     }}                            {   select ?y  {    ?y rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_county_108546183>.           ?y <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Ireland>.                                     }}                            }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/182.sparql", "number": 182, "question": "Which is the largest lake in England?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                               ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_lake_109328904>.  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/area> ?property } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/183.sparql", "number": 183, "question": "Are the cities that River Thames crosses more than 10?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x (COUNT(distinct ?x) as ?total > 10) where {       ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_city_108524735>.         <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/River_Thames> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?x.           } \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/184.sparql", "number": 184, "question": "Are there any rivers that cross both England and Wales?", "answer": "   ASK where {      ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.         ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.          ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Wales>.             } \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/185.sparql", "number": 185, "question": "Which county of England occupies the largest area?", "answer": "   select ?x ?property where {    ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_county_108546183>.    ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.     ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/areatotalkm> ?property.          } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/186.sparql", "number": 186, "question": "What is the longest bridge in Scotland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property  where {         ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_bridge_102898711>.     ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.          ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/length> ?property.         } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/187.sparql", "number": 187, "question": "Which hospital is nearest to Calton Hill in Edinburgh?", "answer": "   Select ?hospital (geof:distance(?hospitalWKT, ?CaltonWKT, uom:metre) as ?distance) WHERE { ?hospital a osm:Hospital ; geo:hasGeometry ?hospitalGeo . ?hospitalGeo geo:asWKT ?hospitalWKT . <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Edinburgh> geo:hasGeometry ?EdinburghGeo . ?EdinburghGeo geo:asWKT ?EdinburghWKT . ?Calton osm:has_name ?l; geo:hasGeometry ?CaltonGeo . ?CaltonGeo geo:asWKT ?CaltonWKT . filter( str(?l)=\"Calton Hill\"). filter(geof:sfContains(?EdinburghWKT, ?hospitalWKT)). } ORDER BY ASC(?distance) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/188.sparql", "number": 188, "question": "Which is the closest airport to London?", "answer": "   SELECT ?poi WHERE   { SERVICE <http://pyravlos1.di.uoa.gr:8080/geoqa/Query>       { <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London> geo:hasGeometry ?instanceGeom.                          ?instanceGeom geo:asWKT        ?instanceWKT.         ?poi rdf:type osm:Airport ;              geo:hasGeometry ?poiGeom .         ?poiGeom  geo:asWKT        ?poiWKT .            }       BIND(geof:distance(?instanceWKT, ?poiWKT, uom:metre) as ?res)   } ORDER BY ?res LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/189.sparql", "number": 189, "question": "Which is the highest point in Cheshire?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_mountain_109359803>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Cheshire>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/elevationm>  ?property.                                 } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/190.sparql", "number": 190, "question": "Which is the highest building in London?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_building_102913152>.                                  ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/London>.                                 ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasHeight>  ?property.                                  } ORDER BY DESC(xsd:integer(?property)) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/191.sparql", "number": 191, "question": "Is the county of Antrim bigger than the county of Armagh?", "answer": "   select distinct (?a1>?a2) where {                                 <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/County_Antrim> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasArea> ?a1.                                <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/County_Armagh> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasArea> ?a2.  } \n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/192.sparql", "number": 192, "question": "Which is the smallest lake in Scotland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                               ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_lake_109328904>.                                                ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.                                                ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/hasArea> ?property                                                                  } ORDER BY(xsd:double(?property)) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/193.sparql", "number": 193, "question": "Which hotel is the nearest to Old Trafford Stadium in Manchester?", "answer": "   Select ?hotel (geof:distance(?hotelWKT, ?TraffordWKT, uom:metre) as ?distance) WHERE { ?hotel a osm:Hotel ; geo:hasGeometry ?hoteleo . ?hotelGeo geo:asWKT ?hotelWKT . <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Manchester> geo:hasGeometry ?ManchesterGeo . ?ManchesterGeo geo:asWKT ?ManchesterWKT . ?Trafford osm:has_name ?l; geo:hasGeometry ?TraffordGeo ; a osm:Stadium . ?TraffordGeo geo:asWKT ?TraffordWKT . filter( str(?l)=\"Old Trafford\"). filter(geof:sfContains(?ManchesterWKT, ?hotelWKT)). } ORDER BY ASC(?distance) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/194.sparql", "number": 194, "question": "Which county of England has the biggest population?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {                                            ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_county_108546183>.                                     ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.       ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/population> ?property                                               } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/195.sparql", "number": 195, "question": "Which Welsh district has the most adjacent Welsh districts?", "answer": "SELECT  ?district1name (count(?district2) as ?count)           \nWHERE\n  {  SERVICE <http://pyravlos1.di.uoa.gr:8080/geoqa/Query> {\n            ?district1  a <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_UnitaryAuthority> ;\n                        gadm:hasName ?district1name ;\n                        geo:hasGeometry [ geo:asWKT ?district1WKT ] .\n            ?district2  a <http://kr.di.uoa.gr/yago2geo/ontology/OS_UnitaryAuthority> ;\n                        gadm:hasName ?district2name ;\n                        geo:hasGeometry [ geo:asWKT ?district2WKT ] .\n            filter( (geof:sfTouches(?district1WKT, ?district2WKT))  &&\n                      (?district1 != ?district2) ).\n        }\n}\nGROUP BY ?district1name\nORDER BY DESC(?count)\nLIMIT 1"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/196.sparql", "number": 196, "question": "Which town has the biggest population in Scotland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {         ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_town_108665504>.                                                                            ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.                                     ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/population> ?property                                    } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/197.sparql", "number": 197, "question": "Which is the longest river in Scotland?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x ?property where {       ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_river_109411430>.                                                                            ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Scotland>.                                     ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/infobox/en/length> ?property                                   } ORDER BY DESC(?property) LIMIT 1\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/198.sparql", "number": 198, "question": "Which towns of England have at least two hospitals?", "answer": "   select distinct ?x (count(DISTINCT ?y) as ?count) where {                                                                                                                  ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_town_108665504>.                                     ?y rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_hospital_103540595>.                                                                            ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/England>.                                     ?y <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> ?x.                                                         } GROUP BY ?x HAVING (count(DISTINCT ?y) > 1)\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/199.sparql", "number": 199, "question": "Are there more than 10 districts in Hampshire, England ?", "answer": "   select (count(distinct ?x) >10)  where {         ?x rdf:type <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/wordnet_district_108552138>.       ?x <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/isLocatedIn> <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Hampshire>.                         }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/200.sparql", "number": 200, "question": "What London underground stations are closest to the British Museum?", "answer": "   SELECT ?poi ?wkt WHERE { ?poi rdf:type osm:Railway_Station. ?poi geo:hasGeometry ?geom . ?geom geo:asWKT ?wkt . ?instance rdf:type osm:Museum . ?instance osm:has_name \"British Museum\"^^<http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#string> . ?instance geo:hasGeometry ?inGeom . ?inGeom geo:asWKT ?inWKT . FILTER (geof:distance(?wkt, ?inWKT, <http://www.opengis.net/def/uom/OGC/1.0/metre>) < 500 ) . }\n"}, {"href": "https://geoqa.di.uoa.gr/assets/queries/201.sparql", "number": 201, "question": "What is the distance between Liverpool and Glasgow?", "answer": "   SELECT (geof:distance(?livWKT, ?glasWKT, <http://www.opengis.net/def/uom/OGC/1.0/metre>) AS ?dist) WHERE { <http://yago-knowledge.org/resource/Liverpool> geo:hasGeometry ?livGeom .  ?livGeom geo:asWKT ?livWKT . <http://yago-knowledge/resource/Glasgow> geo:hasGeometry ?glasGeom . ?glasGeom geo:asWKT ?glasWKT . }"}]